<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oscar Bjorkman</title>
    <description>Oscar Bjorkman&#39;s School Posts
</description>
    <link>http://stereopoly.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://stereopoly.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 13:27:43 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 13:27:43 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Trans-Pacific Slave Trade</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-trans-pacific-slave-trade&quot;&gt;The Trans-Pacific Slave Trade&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-link---15-minute-historyhttp15minutehistoryorg20160113episode-76-the-trans-pacific-slave-trade&quot;&gt;Article Link - &lt;a href=&quot;http://15minutehistory.org/2016/01/13/episode-76-the-trans-pacific-slave-trade/&quot;&gt;15 Minute History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the Trans-Pacific Slave trade?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the Manila Galleon?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who is Diego De la Cruz?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where is Manila?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connections&quot;&gt;Connections&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trans-Pacific slave trade relates to WWI in which there was a lot of fighting and wars between the Spanish and hte natives. They converted all the people to Christianity and this was tough at times. The slave trade led to improved technologies, like slave galleon ships, just like WWI led to a lot of new modern technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-knowledge&quot;&gt;New Knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Manila Galleon is an annual flotilla between Manila and Acapulco.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The article describes the life of Diego de la Cruz, a slave who managed to escape slavery in Central America.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Spanish chose Manila as a new capital because it was near China and was very easy for them to join the trading network. Manila was also a good location to start converting all of Asia to Christianity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 05:55:55 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://stereopoly.github.io/2016/05/23/16-ww1-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stereopoly.github.io/2016/05/23/16-ww1-blog.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>North Korea Human Rights</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;north-korea-freedom-of-information-and-opinion&quot;&gt;North Korea Freedom of Information and Opinion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-link---15-minute-historyhttpsfreedomhouseorgreportfreedom-press2015north-korea&quot;&gt;Article Link - &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedomhouse.org/report/freedom-press/2015/north-korea&quot;&gt;15 Minute History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where is North Korea?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How is the right being violated?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who is North Korea’s leader?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does North Korea do about the right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connections&quot;&gt;Connections&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our class, we learned about WWI and how there was a lot of propaganda being created about fighting in the war. People created a lot of posters and advertisement recruiting men to fight the glorious war. North Korea does similar style of propaganda, telling the people in their country how amazing they are and how the rest of the world is terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;information&quot;&gt;Information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Press Freedom index rates North Korea 97/100, with 100 being the worst.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Press Status is officially noted as ‘Not Free’.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;North Korea’s freedom of information and opinion gained attention after the regime threatened war on the United States over a comedy called the Interview, depicting an attempt to assassinate Kim Jong Un.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;North Korea’s citizens secretly tune into foreign radios and TV stations, to get uncensored information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 18:25:55 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://stereopoly.github.io/2016/05/22/16-human-rights.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stereopoly.github.io/2016/05/22/16-human-rights.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Legacy of Imperialism</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-legacy-of-imperialism&quot;&gt;The Legacy of Imperialism&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-link---reutershttpwwwreuterscomarticleus-india-independence-legacy-idussp29531720070815&quot;&gt;Article Link - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/us-india-independence-legacy-idUSSP29531720070815&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many people in India speak English?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What did the Bangalore-based firm announce?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the Indian Administrative Service?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cricket, the sport, has done what for India?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connections&quot;&gt;Connections:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source relates to the Imperialism effects we have been learning about in India. We had a debate about whether or not Imperialism helped or hurt India more. This article writes about the longer lasting effects of British Imperialism on India. It shows a new perspective, because Reuters is a British news company, which may be biased towards the British people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-knowledge&quot;&gt;New Knowledge:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English is the number one language in India, and may not have been if the British hadn’t come to imperialize. Several firms within India have reached out to other countries, creating software to help them learn English too. The British gave India the notion of law, a parliamentary democracy, and constitutional government, an organized civil service, police force, military, and the legal system. All the key institutions were brought about to India by the British. Laws created by the British when they imperialize India haven’t changed much since. The most damaging legacy, is that the government setup by the British was not to run a 1 billion people country, but a relatively small colony.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 01:55:55 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://stereopoly.github.io/2016/03/18/16-imperialism-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stereopoly.github.io/2016/03/18/16-imperialism-post.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Current Events Assignment</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;north-korea-brutality&quot;&gt;North Korea Brutality&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-link---cnnhttpwwwcnncom20151210asiaun-north-korea-meeting&quot;&gt;Article Link - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/2015/12/10/asia/un-north-korea-meeting/&quot;&gt;CNN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This CNN article describes North Korea and how criminals, rebels, and foreign nationals are tortured in horrible conditions. 8 torture methods are described, including solitary confinement in a 1 meter by 1.2 meter box, holding a set position until exhaustion, and beatings until vomiting blood. The article calls out North Korea for their human rights violations and wants them to face international criminal court. Up to now, only a warning has been given by the UN and no action has been taken in court due to China and Russia resisting such action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;human-rights-impact&quot;&gt;Human Rights Impact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The human rights violations described impact practically all of the 30 human rights we have. The torture methods wear you down to the bare bones and you are always on the brink of death. No where near adequate food is provided. The humans rights are virtually nonexistent in these torture chambers. The prisoners have no say or due process in court. Most countries look down upon North Korea’s leadership due to them ignoring human rights of their prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;future-actions-to-improve-human-rights&quot;&gt;Future Actions to Improve Human Rights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments have already called North Korea out on their horrible human rights laws and how they treat their people. Their ruler hasn’t responded at all and hasn’t tried to improve the conditions of the people of North Korea. We need to take Kim Jong Un to international court about these human rights violations. Meanwhile, we can help the people of North Korea by supporting humanitarian organizations working in North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/pic1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;picture-link---picturehttpcdnnewsapicomauimagev1externalurlhttp3a2f2fcontent6videonewscomau2fwyow9uddrnh8m27s6cym-barbfoq78l52fpromo253965594width650apikeykq7wnrk4eun47vz9c5xuj3mc&quot;&gt;Picture Link - &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.newsapi.com.au/image/v1/external?url=http%3A%2F%2Fcontent6.video.news.com.au%2FwyOW9udDrnh8M27S6cym-BARBfOQ78L5%2Fpromo253965594&amp;amp;width=650&amp;amp;api_key=kq7wnrk4eun47vz9c5xuj3mc&quot;&gt;Picture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 21:55:55 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://stereopoly.github.io/2016/01/06/16-current-events.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stereopoly.github.io/2016/01/06/16-current-events.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fall Semester Reflection</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;epic-rap-battle-of-history-reflection&quot;&gt;Epic Rap Battle of History Reflection&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Link - &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0BzEqU4Z2AwHsUk5LU0NzM2JIeFk/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;backward-looking&quot;&gt;Backward Looking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past I have done several movies for a variety of subjects like science and history. In 7th grade, I did a movie about our solar system and how it affects humans and animals on Earth. Comparing it to the rap battle I made this fall, it was not as good. The rap battle had both a movie and a homemade music track, while the science video only had video. I have gotten a lot better at using music mixing software since 7th grade to be able to make this rap battle sound pretty good. In 8th grade history, I made a video using flashcards and I would quickly flash them in front of the screen to make a flipbook style video. It was not very good since everything was very shaky, and the voice recording was very bad. The rap battle that my group and I made had very good sound quality because we recorded with good microphones. The music was also mixed with better software and I have gotten better at it since 8th grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;forward-looking&quot;&gt;Forward Looking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rap battle that I made with my group could be improved in several ways. I think the music of the video should’ve been done as a parody of one song instead of having each of us rap it out. Using a parody would make the music flow better and we could use autotune to make our voices sound amazing. Also, I think our video could be improved. Instead of having large blocks of text on the screen for the reader to view, we could somehow display the text as the music advanced to make it more natural and easier to get the information. As well as improving the video, I think our group could add subtitles to the video so that the listener can hear our voices better since we aren’t that great singers. Finally, the communication outside of school about the project wasn’t very good, so I think we could’ve gotten more done if we had decided to get each other’s numbers. This would have allowed us to set up meetings outside of class time to work on the project and make it even better.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 15:56:45 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://stereopoly.github.io/2015/12/16/fallsemester-reflection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stereopoly.github.io/2015/12/16/fallsemester-reflection.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>illuminati</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-illuminati&quot;&gt;The illuminati&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Illuminati&quot;&gt;Illuminati&lt;/a&gt;: This source has data, pictures, and written descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.illuminatirex.com/illuminati-symbol-great-seal-one-dollar-bill/&quot;&gt;Illuminati Conspiracy Theories&lt;/a&gt;: This source has pictures and written descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How did the illuminati form?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What caused the illuminati to be formed?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who founded the illuminati?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What did the illuminati do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;connections&quot;&gt;Connections:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our class, we have been learning about religion and how the Renaissance has affected it. The illuminati is a secret group that was created by and for people who thought against the Church. This relates to what we have been learning because the people in the Renaissance are starting to turn away from the Church and think on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-knowledge&quot;&gt;New Knowledge:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The illuminati was formed by a man named Adam Weishaupt. It was formed to oppose superstition, obscurantism, religious influence in life, and the abuse of state power. They, and other secret societies were outlawed, but still continued underground and were responsible for the French Revolution.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The illuminati now refers to organizations who claim to be secret societies and are pushing for the same goal. They have been alleged to have tried to gain political power and influence by planting secret agents. These lead to some conspiracy theories about the illuminati in the shadows of various TV shows and the dollar bill.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are various conspiracy theories about the dollar bill. For example, the pyramid on the dollar bill is very similar to the Bavarian Illuminati pyramid. If you circle various letters on the text around the pyramid, you get the word Mason. There are 13 steps on the pyramid, 13 stars on the seal, 13 letters in E Pluribus Unum, 13 arrows on the seal, 13 leaves on the seal, and 13 berries on the seal. These all relate to the 13 bloodlines of the illuminati.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 16:56:45 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://stereopoly.github.io/2015/09/17/illuminati.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stereopoly.github.io/2015/09/17/illuminati.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-help&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s dedicated Help repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 16:34:01 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://stereopoly.github.io/2015/09/06/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://stereopoly.github.io/2015/09/06/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
